Adventure is reborn.
The Mummy Returns is a adventure, action, fantasy
film directed by Stephen Sommers.
Rick and Evelyn O’Connell, along with their 8-year-old son Alex, discover the key to
the legendary Scorpion King’s might: the fabled Bracelet of Anubis.
Unfortunately, a newly resurrected Imhotep has designs on the bracelet as well, and isn’t above
kidnapping its new bearer, Alex, to gain control of Anubis’s otherworldly army.
Rick O'Connell, played by Brendan Fraser.
Evelyn O'Connell / Nefertiri, played by Rachel Weisz.
Jonathan Carnahan, played by John Hannah.
Ardeth Bay, played by Oded Fehr.
Imhotep, played by Arnold Vosloo.
Meela / Anck-Su-Namun, played by Patricia Velásquez.
The Mummy Returns is a 2001 American fantasy action-adventure
film written and directed by Stephen Sommers.
It is the sequel to the 1999 film The Mummy, and
the second in The Mummy film series.
Brendan Fraser, Rachel Weisz, John Hannah, Arnold Vosloo, Oded Fehr, and Patricia Velásquez reprise their roles from the previous
film, with Dwayne Johnson (credited under his ring name "The Rock") joining the cast in his film acting debut.
The film was released on May 4, 2001, by Universal Pictures.
Like its predecessor, The Mummy Returns was a commercial success, grossing $435 million worldwide,
becoming the seventh-highest-grossing film of 2001 and the highest-grossing film of the series.
The film received mixed reviews from critics.
It was followed by a 2002 prequel film, The Scorpion King and a
2008 sequel, The Mummy: Tomb of the Dragon Emperor.
The film explores themes of egypt, pyramid, son, mummy, nile.